A Guide to the McGavock Family Papers, 1751-1961
Special Collections, Kegley Library, Wytheville Community College
- Series II. Financial and Legal Records. 1804-1942., 53 folders
  Series includes wills of James McGavock Sr., Josiah Ramsey, James McGavock Jr., James McGavock III, Mary McGavock, Cynthia McGavock, Stephen McGavock, Joseph Cloyd McGavock, James Hampton McGavock, and Cloyd McGavock (Folders 1-10). Folder 11 contains summons while Folder 12 has judgments. Account books (Folders 13-18), insurance politics (Folders 19-21), stocks and securities (Folders 22-26), Confederate vouchers (Folder 27), cancelled checks (Folder 28), tax receipts and returns (Folders 29-22), and bills and receipts (Folders 34-53) complete the series.
- Series III. Land Records. 1751 - 1903., 21 folders.
  Series includes deeds and indentures (Folders 1-13), plats and surveys (Folders 14-18), Maury and McGavock and Max Meadows Land and Improvement Company records (Folders 19-20), and land records of William H. Pointer (Folder 21).
- Series IV. Miscellaneous Records. 1772-1951., 17 folders.
  Series includes records on politics, American Red Cross, school compositions, advertisements, inventory of John Neely estate, petition of Botetourt County residents for new county (1772), bills - Thomas Jefferson to William Rutherford (1770) and James Madison to John Rutherford (undated).
- Series V. Books. 1890-1893., 18 items.
  Includes medical notebooks of Edward Pointer McGavock, Bible of Elizabeth Pointer McGavock, and notebook of Randal McGavock.
- Series VI. Photographs. Undated., 7 folders.
  Series includes photographs of Ephraim McGavock, Cloyd McGavock and other family members; many unidentified.